<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.slimture.dopeIPTV</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>dopeIPTV</name>
  <summary>Modern IPTV player for Xtream Codes with EPG</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      dopeIPTV is a clean, modern player for your own Xtream Codes or M3U
      subscription. It offers an embedded mpv player, an electronic programme
      guide with a timeline grid, movies and series with TMDB metadata,
      recording and timeshift catch-up, optional Trakt sync, Chromecast
      support, multiple playlists, themes and translations.
    </p>
    <p>
      dopeIPTV is a player only: it does not provide any channels or content -
      you connect it to a service you already subscribe to.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.slimture.dopeIPTV.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Live TV with the electronic programme guide</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/slimture/dopeIPTV/main/docs/screenshots/live.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Themes: five palettes and seven accent colors</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/slimture/dopeIPTV/main/docs/screenshots/themes.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>The EPG timeline grid: what's on now and next</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/slimture/dopeIPTV/main/docs/screenshots/epg-grid.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption>Favorites and the embedded player</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/slimture/dopeIPTV/main/docs/screenshots/player.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <categories>
    <category>AudioVideo</category>
    <category>Video</category>
    <category>TV</category>
  </categories>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/slimture/dopeiptv</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/slimture/dopeiptv/issues</url>
  <developer id="io.github.slimture">
    <name>dopeIPTV contributors</name>
  </developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.7.2" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Windows joins Linux and macOS, plus timeshift and UI fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>A portable Windows x64 build (unzip and run, no installer), and a fix for a crash on exit in the windowed build</li>
          <li>Channels that advertise catch-up but don't actually serve it now hide the timeshift affordance instead of leaving a dead rewind button and seek bar behind an "archive unavailable" message</li>
          <li>The category search magnifier now sits centred in its button</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.1" date="2026-07-14">
      <description>
        <p>A UI/UX polish release: a redesigned, responsive left panel and a calmer timeshift player.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Redesigned left panel with icons and a collapsible Library group; a layout that never overflows or overlaps at any window size</li>
          <li>The timeshift timeline auto-hides after a few idle seconds and reappears on interaction</li>
          <li>Accent colours follow your chosen theme everywhere, including the middle-column progress bar and playing highlights</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.7.0" date="2026-07-14">
      <description>
        <p>Timeshift and catch-up TV, a reminders manager, search everywhere, and rock-solid playback.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Timeshift and catch-up - a live timeline to scrub back into a channel's archive, DVR-style pause of live TV, and play a specific past programme; the app learns each channel's real archive depth and recovers from over-deep requests</li>
          <li>Reminders manager to find and multi-delete programme reminders, plus programme search across the whole guide and a configurable number of upcoming programmes</li>
          <li>Search everywhere - category search that also matches the channels inside a category, and left-column search in Favorites, Watch Later, Watched, Recordings and History</li>
          <li>Customizable keyboard shortcuts with sensible per-OS defaults</li>
          <li>Software decoding is now the default (like standalone mpv) for playback that never glitches; hardware decoding is an opt-in setting with an automatic software fallback</li>
          <li>Editable recording title and description, faster channel switching, and fixes for an exit crash, macOS arrow scrubbing and Picture-in-Picture</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.4" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>Stability and housekeeping: smooth 4K, no bloat over time, and self-healing live TV.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Smooth 4K playback - the periodic stutter is fixed (resume-position and caches moved out of the main settings file), and hardware decoding is used across GPUs</li>
          <li>No bloat over time - TMDB caches are capped, EPG guides are gzip-compressed on disk, and orphaned guides are cleaned up at startup</li>
          <li>Live TV reconnects on drop instead of freezing, with a toggle for single-connection accounts; double-click to play a channel, a last-channel key, and type-a-number to jump</li>
          <li>Continue watching for movies and episodes, Recently added, programme reminders, and a discreet once-a-day update indicator</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.3" date="2026-07-11">
      <description>
        <p>Keyboard shortcuts, a calmer progress indicator, and playback stability.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Keyboard shortcuts throughout - Ctrl+G for the EPG guide, M/P/R/I for mute/PiP/record/stats, arrow keys to zap and nudge volume, and N/Enter in the guide (all documented in the README)</li>
          <li>A steadier progress indicator that no longer sticks at "100%" or lingers on screen, with a watchdog to clear it</li>
          <li>Playback stability - live streams auto-reconnect after a network hiccup, a stall watchdog recovers a frozen picture, and moving the window no longer drops the stream</li>
          <li>Packaging - a fully offline Flathub manifest so the app can ship on Flathub</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.2" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p>A polish release: a collapsible sidebar, custom colours, and fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Collapsible sidebar - fold it to a slim icon rail (drag or Ctrl+B), plus a focus mode that hides the list for a player-only layout</li>
          <li>Custom colours for the left-column entries, categories, individual items, and favourite folders (a folder's colour applies to all its favourites)</li>
          <li>M3U playlists now auto-detect their EPG guide (url-tvg), and gzipped XMLTV guides are read transparently</li>
          <li>The EPG grid marks channels with catch-up, flags the channel you're watching, and offers "Play this programme"; click the sidebar logo to jump to what's playing</li>
          <li>Fixes: Picture-in-Picture close no longer quits the app, the mini player keeps its size after fullscreen, and the colour picker no longer freezes on some Linux setups</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.1" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p>A polish release: a collapsible sidebar, custom colours, and fixes.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Collapsible sidebar - fold it to a slim icon rail (drag or Ctrl+B), plus a focus mode that hides the list for a player-only layout</li>
          <li>Custom colours for the left-column entries, categories, individual items, and favourite folders (a folder's colour applies to all its favourites)</li>
          <li>M3U playlists now auto-detect their EPG guide (url-tvg), and gzipped XMLTV guides are read transparently</li>
          <li>The EPG grid flags the channel you're watching, with a button to jump back to it</li>
          <li>Fixes: closing while in Picture-in-Picture no longer quits the app, and the colour picker no longer freezes on some Linux setups</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.6.0" date="2026-07-10">
      <description>
        <p>A big feature release focused on getting started, Trakt and the EPG.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>One-click "Sign in with Trakt" via the browser - no codes or API keys</li>
          <li>Try it with built-in demo channels, or add any free M3U playlist</li>
          <li>Movies and episodes auto-mark as watched once you've seen them</li>
          <li>A new horizontal EPG timeline grid with timeshift catch-up</li>
          <li>Unified favorite folders across channels, movies and series</li>
          <li>Adaptive window sizing, an in-app update check, and a recordings size cap</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.0" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>A large internal reorganisation - no user-visible change, but a
           much cleaner and safer codebase to build on.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The code is grouped into clear layers (providers, core,
              media, services, ui) with a one-way import rule, so a module
              can be changed without breaking the layers beneath it</li>
          <li>Business logic that did not belong in the window (cover-art
              resolution, resume positions) is now separate, tested
              service objects</li>
          <li>The Python wheel now ships every subpackage, and the tree
              passes a clean lint with no dead imports</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.4" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>Lower memory use, ARM64 Linux builds, and an internal cleanup.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Far lower memory use: the EPG index is stored compactly
              (roughly a quarter of before on big guides) and image caches
              are capped by size, so idle RAM drops by around a gigabyte
              with large providers</li>
          <li>Faster EPG lookups (binary search instead of scanning),
              snappier lists on huge channel line-ups</li>
          <li>ARM64 Linux builds: an aarch64 AppImage and .deb, for ARM
              machines (e.g. an ARM Ubuntu VM on Apple Silicon)</li>
          <li>Internal restructuring of the main window into focused modules
              - no user-visible change, but a safer base for new features</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.3" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>The embedded player is now fully self-contained.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Bundle libmpv's own dependencies (ffmpeg, libass, ...), so
              in-app video works on any machine - not only where a matching
              mpv/ffmpeg is already installed. Fixes a black or disabled
              player on, e.g., a fresh Ubuntu 24.04</li>
          <li>Never crash if the graphics stack can't create the video
              surface - the app stays up and offers external playback</li>
          <li>CI now verifies the player loads inside a clean container</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.2" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>Packaging fixes so the app "just works" on more systems.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Embedded video now works across distributions - the Linux
              builds no longer ship their own OpenGL/Mesa stack, which had
              clashed with the host driver and left a black player on Ubuntu</li>
          <li>AppImage runs with no libfuse2 install needed (static runtime)</li>
          <li>External mpv/VLC launches correctly from the packaged builds</li>
          <li>Flatpak no longer crashes on libmpv builds missing an option</li>
          <li>Silenced the fontconfig warning spam on launch</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.1" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>Bugfix: the embedded player is now included in the packaged
           builds.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Bundle libmpv under the exact soname the player loads, so
              the in-app video player works in the AppImage/.deb/.dmg
              (0.4.0 shipped it under the wrong name on Linux)</li>
          <li>CI now fails the build if libmpv isn't bundled correctly</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.4.0" date="2026-07-09">
      <description>
        <p>Metadata, Trakt and favourites overhaul.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Built-in TMDB artwork - posters work out of the box, no account needed</li>
          <li>Trakt cross-device watched sync for movies, episodes and whole series</li>
          <li>New Watched category split into Local and Trakt</li>
          <li>Favourites for movies and series, with a Channels/Movies/Series split and Trakt list sync</li>
          <li>Watch Later markers, watched badges, and richer covers throughout</li>
          <li>Prompt before recording a different channel than the one playing</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.3.1" date="2026-07-08"/>
    <release version="0.3.0" date="2026-07-08"/>
  </releases>
</component>
